Rajeshwari Adi

Boston, USA | +1 857 340 7719 | rajeshwari.adi2698@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/r-adi/ | github.com/r-adi09

OBJECTIVE

An Enthusiastic MS in CS student with 2 years of SDE experience. Proficient in Java, Spring Boot, Database technologies, MERN stack and cloud technologies like AWS and GCP. Seeking full-time roles in SWE / Cloud / Data Engineering starting January/May 2024

EDUCATION

Northeastern University, Boston, USA

Jan 2022 - May 2024

Master's in Computer Science, GPA: 4.0/4

Osmania University, Hyderabad, India

Aug 2016 - Aug 2020

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science and Engineering, GPA: 9.2/10

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript, Go, HTML, CSS, SQL, GraphQL, PostgreSQL, TypeScript

Frameworks: Spring Boot, Angular, Vue.js, Flask, Django, jQuery, JUnit, Mockito, Hadoop, MapReduce

Libraries: ReactJS, Bootstrap, Scikit-learn, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib

Web and Cloud Technologies: AWS, EC2, DynamoDB, Azure, AngularJS, Node.js, Express, React, Redux, XML, JSON, RESTful web services, Git, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Maven, CI/CD, Google Cloud Platform

WORK EXPERIENCE

MathWorks, Software Engineer Intern, Natick, Massachusetts, USA

Jan 2023 - May 2023

- Implemented new features by building **RESTful microservices** in **JAVA** with **Spring Boot** for the Internal tools team, enabling automation of various components, decreasing incident resolution time by 40%
- Improved APIs performance with **Hibernate** projections markedly minimizing retrieval time from 16 to 2 seconds
- Orchestrated the integration of Swagger ecosystem into codebase, reducing communication overhead, API usage issues
- Devised an extensive test suite in **JUnit** and **JMockit** to achieve a 100% code coverage and heightened code reliability

Northeastern University, Graduate Teaching Assistant

May 2022 - Dec 2022

- Taught fundamental concepts in mobile application development, including data storage, API integrations, UI/UX
- Managed pull requests, executed thorough code reviews for mobile app projects, adhering to best coding practices

Deloitte, Software Developer, Hyderabad, India

Aug 2020 - Nov 2021

- Developed KPI dashboards for a major oil and gas conglomerate leveraging JAVA, AngularJS, Node.js, SAP OData optimizing business insights for stakeholders with critical data insights through user-friendly dashboards
- Implemented CI/CD pipelines using Git, Jenkins, Kubernetes reducing deployment time by 50% with seamless releases
- Automated project reports and file updates with RPA in Blue Prism, simplifying manual effort by 80%
- Spearheaded a team of 10 new hires, conducted knowledge transfer workshops in **JavaScript** for onboarding
- Awarded 'Applause Award' twice in a row for delivering highly reliable dashboards adhering to tight deadlines

Cisco Systems, Software Engineer Intern, Bangalore, India

Jan 2020 - Jun 2020

- Revamped a web application utilizing **Java**, **MVC**, **Spring Boot**, **HTML** and **CSS** to analyze system-generated logs from Cisco's ASA firewall through **RESTful APIs**, facilitating expedited troubleshooting of customer networks
- Improved product recommendations for distinct Cisco ISE versions by 30%, constructing a dashboard to monitor bug occurrences across versions leveraging **Python**, **Flask**, **MongoDB**, matplotlib, and Plotly

Microsoft, Software Developer Mentee - WISE Program, Hyderabad, India

Sep 2018 - Sep 2019

- Architected and built an Android application, 'Smart Scheduler' with JAVA and Azure, incorporating decision trees algorithm
 to help users prioritize and schedule tasks based on user preferences resulting in a 40% increase in task management
- Optimized user experience by designing an intuitive UI prototype in AdobeXD and conducting usability tests

PROJECTS

Blogs App Microservices Backend – JAVA | Spring Boot | JWT | AWS - Github

Jul 2023

- Developed a robust backend system for a Blogs App using Java Spring Boot and microservices architecture. Designed a variety
 of APIs to manage blog-related operations efficiently and securely
- Integrated JWT authentication to ensure secure access to the APIs, enhancing user privacy and data integrity

Tuiter - Full Stack Web Application - React | Node | MongoDB | Express - Github

Dec 2022

- Created a dynamic web application like 'Twitter' allowing users to perform comprehensive CRUD operations utilizing ReactJS with Redux to build front-end, with efficient state management and real-time updates
- Employed NodeJS, Express to create Restful APIs enabling robust communication between front-end and database

Kill Doctor Lucky Board Game – JAVA | MVC | Git | JUnit - Github

Apr 2022

- Devised an interactive multiplayer board game based on Kill Doctor Lucky board game in Java applying object-oriented design principles, MVC architecture, Facade and command design patterns
- Employed TDD approach to construct a full JUnit test suite to test model and controller thoroughly using mocking